I like you.
我喜欢你
Repeat.
重复
No, you don't like me at all.
不 你根本不喜欢我
- I mean... - Don't move.
我是
The device is expensive.
设备很贵
I really like you.
我明明就喜欢你
When one's passion is aroused,
人心动的时候
their ventral tegmental area
侧腹被盖区
and caudate nucleus will be activated.
和尾状核区会激活
Near-infrared brain function image results
近红外脑功能成像检测
show that,
结果显示
when you said you liked me,
你说你喜欢我的时候
those parts of your brain were unresponsive.
这些脑穴毫无反应
So you don't like me at all.
所以你根本就不喜欢我
My data
我 我的数据
didn't change
之所以没有变化
because the bad environment
是因为这儿环境不好
affected my mood.
我的心情受到了影响
My brain activities
大脑活动
were naturally depressed.
自然会受到抑制的
I know that
我自己知道
I do like you.
我明明就是喜欢你的
How can you prove that
你怎么证明
it's caused by external factors
是因外界因素导致的
rather than
而不是
you don't like me at all?
你根本就不喜欢我
When
我
I see you,
看见你的时候
my heart beats faster.
心跳会加快
There are many reasons for the rapid heartbeat.
心跳加速有很多原因
Pressure,
压力
anxiety,
焦虑
lack of sleep,
睡眠不足
and stimulating beverage
刺激性饮料
can all accelerate heartbeat.
都可以导致心跳加速
I blush when I see you.
我看见你会脸红
I dream of you
我晚上睡觉
at night.
还会梦见你呢
Blushed face may indicate
脸红可能是因为
cervical spondylosis.
你有颈椎病
Cervical displacement stimulates sympathetic nerve,
颈部移位刺激交感神经
As for dreams,
做梦
there are even more reasons.
就有更多原因了
How do you want me to prove that
那你要我怎么证明
I like you?
我喜欢你
Now that you've joined our lab
既然你来到我们实验室
and become
作为我们
a member of our research group,
实验小组的一员
we should use scientific methods
就得用科学的方法
to prove it.
来证明
Like, do experiments.
做实验
to prove I like you?
证明我喜欢你
I'm Su Chengcheng,
我叫苏澄澄
majoring in biomedical engineering at
现在在东南科技大学
Southeast Science and Technology University
生物医学工程专业
as a sophomore.
读大二
Back then,
当初
[Southeast Science and Technology University]
我超常发挥
I excelled myself
考到这所一流大学
I thought with a 7:1 male to female ratio
本以为在这所男女比例
in the university,
七比一的学校
[Males account for 86 percent]
总能邂逅一场
relationship finally.
浪漫的爱情
But I didn't expect that
却不知竟然有
80% of the boys here
百分之八十的男生
had no intention of dating.
根本没有谈恋爱的打算
They only want to live happily
只想跟好哥们一起
with their buddies.
快乐生活
Sit tight.
坐稳了
And the remaining 20%
而剩下百分之二十
who do want to date...
想谈恋爱的男生呢
This is the first hammer I forged
这是我在金工实习课上
[Professing his feelings]
打造的第一把锤子
I think it's very commemorative.
我觉得特别有纪念意义
It's for you.
送给你
The girl on the back seat of the bike
自行车后座上的这位
is my roommate, Li Meizi.
是我的室友李梅子
She always boasts that she's a love expert.
她总是自诩为恋爱专家
But in fact, she's never
其实跟我一样
dated anyone, just like me.
一次恋爱都没谈过
When I was a freshman,
大一
I had no clue what I wanted.
我浑浑噩噩度过一年
Now I'm a sophomore.
现在大二
I've set myself three objectives.
我给自己定下三个目标
[Three objectives of Su Chengcheng]
第一个目标就是
I must have a
一定要谈一场
passionate romance.
轰轰烈烈的恋爱
Today is the annual
今天是一年一度的
homecoming party,
新学联谊会
the best chance to achieve the objective.
是实现目标的最佳时机
Having learned from last year's failure,
总结了去年的失败经验
I decided that
我决定今年
I wouldn't await my doom.
不再坐以待毙
I'm going to make the first move.
我要主动出击
I hope I win the first battle.
希望我首战告捷吧
Target locked. Strike!
目标锁定 出击
Hello,
你好
do you have a lighter?
请问一下你有打火机吗
All right.
行吧
It's like the little flame of love
这就像我们之间的
between us has
爱情小火苗
gone out.
灭了
The new target is in sight.
新目标出现
Strike with all strength.
全力出击
Hello.
你好
Do you have a lighter?
请问你有打火机吗
Yes.
有有有
Sit down.
你们坐
May I have your WeChat?
那我俩加个微信吧
Hello,
同学你好
I'm from the Normal University next to your campus.
我是隔壁师大的
Could you unscrew the cap for me?
你能帮我拧一下瓶盖吗
Warning. Warning.
警报 警报
- Backdoor is attacked. - Sure.
有人偷塔
Our base is attacked.
我方水晶正在被攻击
Thanks.
谢谢
As expected,
不出所料
another failure.
又失败了
This is another roommate of mine,
这是我的另一个室友
Xie Xiaomeng.
谢晓梦
[Xie Xiaomeng]
她长相甜美
gentle personality,
性格温柔
distinctive demeanour,
气质出众
outstanding performance,
成绩优异
She is the dream girlfriend
是全东大
of many boys in our university.
众多男生的梦想
Bro Ying,
颖哥
how do you like my necklace?
你看我这条项链怎么样
Lin Ying
林颖
has never bothered herself
她从来没有
with such a low-brow trouble as dating.
恋爱这种庸俗的烦恼
She focuses wholeheartedly on study
一心只想搞学习
and wins first place in every exam.
次次考试都第一
That's why we call her respectfully
所以我们都尊称她为
Bro Ying.
颖哥
That's how it's solved.
应该这么做呀
I should've thought of it earlier.
我早应该想到的呀
You're back.
你们回来啦
Did the party go well?
联谊顺利吗
She doesn't have to rub it in.
真是哪壶不开提哪壶
It seems that I'm not suitable
看来我终究不适合
for a relationship.
谈恋爱
I'd better sleep well
我还是好好睡觉
and focus on my study.
安心搞学习吧
I mustn't fail any exam.
不挂科才是最重要的
OK.
好吧
I overslept again.
又睡过头了
Su Chengcheng,
苏澄澄
your name will be called soon.
马上就要点到了
Have you come yet?
你来没来呀
The lecturer is famous for letting students fail the exams.
这老师可是名挂哈
Coming late for once,
迟到一次
you'll lose all your class performance grades.
平时分就全完了
Oh, no.
糟糕
The chain is off again.
车链子又掉了
What should I do?
怎么办 怎么办
I'm going downhill.
前方是下坡路
The teaching building is 300 meters away.
还有三百米就是教学楼
At the current speed,
按照现在的速度
I can probably freewheel down there.
应该也可以直接滑过去
Hey,
同学
your chain fell on the ground.
你车链子掉地上啦
If I go pick the chain
如果捡了车链子
and then go to the class,
再去上课
I'll definitely be late.
一定会迟到
[Option A: Don't pick up the chain.]
如果不捡
my chain will be lost.
车链子就没了
[It takes 1 min to pick up the chain.]
怎么办 怎么办
He's so cute.
好可爱呀
I'll teach you
我是你们这个学期
analog electronics technique
模拟电子技术
this semester.
这门课程的老师
I'm surnamed Du.
我姓杜
Du Zhuanjia.
我是杜专家
Don't take it wrong.
别误会
My name is Du Zhuanjia.
我的名字就叫杜专家
Biomedical engineering is a
生物医学工程
comprehensive discipline.
是一门综合类的学科
If you learn it well,
学好了
you'll be a pillar
你就是这个时代
of this era,
乃至于
and even our country.
是这个国家的栋梁
If you don't,
学不好
you'll be
那你们就等着
miserable.
脑袋去凉凉
I don't want any of you
我不希望任何一位同学
to take any chance
在我的课上
on my class.
有任何的侥幸的心理
Look over there.
往那边看
Those are your seniors
那边坐着的
of the fourth and fifth grades,
就是你们大四 大五
who have to take
还要赶回来重修的学长
this class again.
和学姐们
I don't care about the passing grade
我不管学校的
set by the university.
分数线是多少
The grade
在我这儿
I set for you is 80.
及格线就是八十分
You'll pass if you score over 80.
过了八十分就算是及格
If you don't pass,
只要不及格
I don't care which grade you're in
我不管你是大几了
or what reasons you have,
我也不管你是什么原因
you must come back
老老实实地回来
and sit there
坐在那儿
to take the class again.
重修
What held Su Chengcheng up?
苏澄澄在磨蹭什么呀
Before the class begins,
上课之前
let's call the roll.
咱们先点个名
Why hasn't she come?
她怎么还没来呀
Gu Chen.
顾晨
Yes.
到
Xie Xiaomeng.
谢晓梦
Su Chengcheng.
苏澄澄
Yes.
到
How many students are called Su Chengcheng?
你们班有几个苏澄澄
Excuse me, sir,
报告老师
only me.
就我一个
I got a sore throat
我是刚才那个嗓子
just now
有点咳嗽
and coughed.
突然卡住了
So I answered twice.
所以出了两声
Today
今天
is the first lesson of your class.
是你们班的第一节课
I won't blame you.
就算了
From now on, in my class,
以后在我的课上
if anyone skips any lesson,
只要有旷课
or answers for others in the roll-call,
还有代点到的行为
their attendance grades will be cleared.
平时成绩一律清零
Take a seat.
你先坐过去吧
Thank you, sir.
谢谢老师
What's wrong with your hands?
你手怎么弄的
Bike chain lube.
车链子油
The trace of love.
爱情来过的痕迹
Yes.
到
Wang Dazhi.
王大志
Thanks.
谢谢
Lin Ying.
林颖
Yes.
到
Chengcheng.
澄澄
It might be fate that made us meet.
这就是命运般的相遇吧
Su Chengcheng.
苏澄澄
What does that boy look like?
那男的长什么样啊
Is he handsome?
帅吗
He wore a helmet.
人家戴着头盔呢
I didn't see him clearly.
看不清长相
But,
但是
I feel
感觉
he's quite cute.
还挺可爱的
Others' chance encounter is always romantic.
人家邂逅都挺浪漫的
Why is yours
怎么一到你这儿
so weird?
这么诡异呢
That's special.
我这叫特别
Special?
特别
Bike chain lube
车链子油
is so special
好特别
and so romantic.
好浪漫哪
The labs for creative credit
创新学分的实验室
are open to selection soon.
马上开始选了
Let's go.
我们先走吧
The early bird gets the worm.
手快有 手慢无
Go to the computer room.
去机房
The net connection is fast there.
那儿网快
Go.
走
Have you got your campus cards?
学生卡都拿了吧
Yes.
拿了
I haven't.
我没拿
I'm going to the dorm to get it.
我回寝室拿一趟吧
I'll meet you there.
你们去那儿等我
OK.
好好好
You go and get in line.
先去排队
Go.
去去去
Here. Here.
这儿这儿这儿
Chengcheng.
澄澄
Hurry up.
快快快
Excuse me.
你好 不好意思
My friends are at the front.
我朋友在前面
Would you let me pass? Thanks.
让我过一下 谢谢
Excuse me,
不好意思
my friends are at the front.
我朋友在前面
Thanks.
谢谢谢谢
Hurry.
快
We can go in now.
可以进了 可以进了
Chengcheng.
澄澄
Don't wait for me.
别等我了
You go in there.
你们快进
Don't step on me. Don't.
别踩我 别踩我
Bike chain boy?
车链子小哥哥
If the first time was a coincidence,
如果第一次是巧合
it must be
那这次
the arrangement of fate this time.
肯定就是命运的安排吧
Chengcheng,
澄澄
here, here.
这儿这儿这儿
How's your network?
你们网好吗
Where is he?
他去哪儿了
Yes!
太棒了
I got it! I got it!
我抢到了 我抢到了
- Did you get it? - I got it.
你抢到了吗
How about you?
你怎么样
Refresh again.
再刷新一下
Chengcheng, did you get it?
澄澄抢到了吗
I can never get a hot meal,
打饭赶不上热乎的
or find a guy that I like,
恋爱找不到喜欢的
or select a lab that wants me.
实验室还抢不到要我的
Do I have to miss
难道我的人生
everything in my life?
就要一直这样错过吗
Don't worry,
没事
Chengcheng.
澄澄
You still have
这次没选上
a second chance.
还有第二次补选呢
Later,
回头呀
you can check with the counselor.
你再问问辅导员
The second chance
第二批补选
is based on
都是按绩点排名
the rank of GPA.
来选择的
If I can't select a lab,
万一选不上实验室
I can't even get enough credits.
学分都修不够
Chengcheng,
澄澄
before I selected the lab,
我选实验室之前
I had done my research.
已经做好功课了
In the past,
往届
those who couldn't select a lab
那些第一轮没有选上的
all took their courses successfully.
最后全都顺利上了
Don't worry.
你放心吧
Listen.
你听一听
Listen to Bro Ying.
听听颖哥说的
Bro Ying is right.
颖哥说得对呀
Moreover,
再说了
you should see it from another perspective.
你得换个角度想想
Think about it.
你想
If you didn't go to the computer room,
你要是没去选实验室
you wouldn't have met
你也遇不见
the bike chain boy,
车链子小哥哥呀
right?
对吧
Sure.
是啊
Lab.
实验室
Why don't we
那要不
go downstairs and have a drink?
咱们去楼下喝点东西
I want to be alone for a while.
我想一个人待会儿
OK.
好吧
I'm leaving.
那我走了
It's such a coincidence.
这也太巧了吧
This is the third time
今天已经第三次
I've seen him today.
遇见他了
I must find him.
我一定要找到他
Student ID?
学号
Let me see.
我看一下
0602.
零六零二
Yes.
对
Some people
有的人生来
are born to be glowing,
就散发着光芒
while some have to
可有的人光是追逐光芒
use all their luck to pursue light.
就用尽了所有的运气
Xiao Yuhe,
肖宇河
This is the first time
这是我第一次
I know his name.
知道他的名字
But why does it sound so familiar?
怎么感觉这么熟悉
Am I
难道
really blessed by fate?
这真是命运之神的眷顾
The mysterious Book of Answers.
神秘的答案之书
If
如果
he's really the one,
他真是我的命定之人
tell me where he is.
快告诉我他在哪儿吧
I thought
我还以为
he was about
他跟我们
the same grade as us,
差不多是同级呢
not expecting
没想到
that he's doing a PhD.
人家都已经是博士了
Of course, Chengcheng.
当然了 澄澄
He's Xiao Yuhe,
那可是肖宇河呀
the top of straight-A students.
大神中的大神
He skipped several grades.
一路跳级跳上来的
I heard that
我听说
he was a postgraduate student
人家本来在麻省理工
in MIT.
读研
In only three years,
三年的时间
he had got five articles published by IEEE,
就在电气与电子工程师协会上
as the leading author.
发表了五篇译作
And his tutor
而且导师
tried to persuade him to study there,
一直留他继续读
promising to give him
说毕了业之后
a teaching job when he graduated.
就给他教职
But for some unknown reason,
但是不知道为什么
he refused and came back
他好像全给拒绝了
directly after his graduation.
毕了业直接回国
At our university,
在我们学校
he's famous.
他可是大红人
How could you not know him?
你竟然不知道
Chengcheng, I tell you what,
澄澄 我跟你说
it doesn't matter whether he's a straight-A student,
大神没那么重要
but it's important that
但是大神长得帅
he's handsome.
那可就太重要了
Don't waste time.
抓紧 抓紧
Xiao Yuhe,
肖宇河
of thousands of students in the university,
东科大好几千人
I met you
我们一天之内
three times in a day.
竟然碰到三次
I can't miss this opportunity.
我不能错失这个机会
My friends,
姐妹们
I've made up my mind.
我决定了
I found this in the bookstore
这是我昨晚在书店
last night.
捡到的
Is it yours, Xiao Yuhe?
是你的吧 师兄
Thanks.
谢谢
Xiao Yuhe,
师兄
may I have your number?
能不能留个联系方式
Do you know me well enough
你认识我吗
to ask for my number?
就问我要联系方式
If you give me your number,
不认识所以才要留嘛
I'll know you well in the future.
以后不就认识了嘛
Why?
为什么
Because
因为
I kinda like you.
我还挺喜欢你的
Hop on.
上车
I'll take you to a place.
我带你去个地方
Laboratory Application Form?
实验室申请表
Fill it in.
填吧
Do I have to
跟你表白
do this to express my feelings for you?
为什么要填这个
Forget it.
不填算了
I'll do it.
我填
Now you've
现在你已经
officially joined our lab.
正式加入实验室了
This is my spare key card.
这是我的备用卡
You'll get yours next week.
你的下周会正式发给你
Report to the lab at 8:00 tomorrow morning.
明早八点来实验室报到
How was your love confession going?
表白怎么样
We couldn't find you anywhere.
怎么找你的时候没影呢
Is there hope?
有戏不
Chengcheng,
澄澄
did you visit the counselor?
你找辅导员了吗
What about your lab?
实验室的事情怎么样了
I've found a lab.
我找到实验室了
What?
什么
Which one did you select?
你选了哪个
Brain and Intelligence.
脑与智
It's
大概
probably
就是
it.
这样了
That lab is under
那个实验室
the direct charge of our college principal,
可是咱们院长
Academician Chen Xiaorong,
陈筱榕院士直接负责
and the supervision of Du Zhuanjia.
杜专家主管的
Those who can be admitted
能进那儿的
are all scientific geniuses.
可都是科研巨佬
And the lab isn't supposed to
而且这个实验室
recruit undergraduates, is it?
不是不招本科生吗
In the past few years, the only one got admitted
前几届唯一一个进去的
was a genius who ranked in the top three
还是一个全系绩点
of the whole department.
排名前三的巨佬
If you can study there,
能进那儿学习
it'll be a piece of cake for you to get
以后保研
a postgraduate recommendation.
可不要太简单了
There's hope, real hope.
有戏 真的有戏
My friend,
我的姐妹
if you get rich and honorable, don't forget me.
苟富贵 勿相忘
When you meet any
见到那些
promising young academic talent
年少有为的学术天才
with a good-looking face
面容俊朗
who indulges in
且沉迷于科研
scientific research,
无法自拔的师兄
don't forget
请不要忘记
you have a single friend.
你还有一个单身的姐妹
Born to be single.
母胎单身
Got it.
我懂
Help me.
救救我
Help you.
救救你
I'll help you.
会去支援你的
Just like that,
就这样
with an ordinary performance,
学业平平无奇
the student who makes
考试全靠突击的我
a frantic last-minute effort to pass exams,
竟然这么稀里糊涂地
blundered into the top lab
来到了全东科大
of the university.
最顶级的实验室
I thought I was favored
原本以为是幸运之神
by luck,
垂青于我
but it wasn't long
不久之后
before I realized that
我才发现
the moment
自从我踏入
I set foot on the lab
这个实验室的那刻起
was the beginning of my nightmare.
便是我噩梦的开始
I told you its limbs couldn't coordinate.
我就说你肢体不协调吧
I was thinking about how to adjust
我是在考虑如何调节
the natural frequency of its body
它的车身固有频率
and the suspension stiffness coefficient.
还有它的悬挂劲度系数
I was absentminded,
我溜号了
or you wouldn't have a chance.
要不然就你
You're funny.
真有意思
No excuse.
借口
Hello,
师兄们好
I'm Su Chengcheng.
我叫苏澄澄
I'm new here
我是因为创新学分
to gain
选实验室
my creative credit.
新来这儿报到的
Hello.
同学你好
What grade are you in?
你现在几年级了
I'm a sophomore.
我大二了
Sophomore?
大二
An undergraduate?
本科
Have you got a GPA of 4.9?
那你绩点四点九了
Not yet.
还没有
Then you must have come to the wrong lab.
那你肯定来错实验室了
I didn't.
我没有来错
Xiao Yuhe asked me to come here.
是肖宇河师兄让我来的
Yuhe?
小肖
You don't have a high GPA,
你绩点也不高
and you're an undergraduate.
还是本科
Why did he recruit you?
他为什么招你进来
He did ask me to come.
真的是他让我来的
He gave me this key card.
这个门禁卡是他给我的
What's your
你跟他
relationship with him?
什么关系
I have nothing to do with him.
我跟他没有关系
Because I said I liked him,
因为我跟他表白了
so he asked me to fill in
所以他让我
an application form
填了个申请表
and let me join the lab.
就让我进来了
Yuhe has never done this before.
这事小肖可从来没做过
Is it because...
这么说难道
Is it?
难道
Chengcheng,
澄澄师妹呀
you're one of us now.
以后咱就是自己人啦
Sure.
是啊
How about
要不
we give you a tour
师兄们带你去参观一下
around the lab?
咱们实验室
I'm going too.
我也去
This is Zhang Li,
这叫张力
The robot dog is his.
这狗是他的
Get back to your work.
你去忙去吧
Let's go.
走走走
Have you printed all the logos?
那标识你打印完了吗
Go print them.
去打印吧
Chengcheng, going forward from here
澄澄 这里往前走
is Prof. Du's office.
这个是杜老师的办公室
Yes.
对对对
I'm Liu Dongmao,
我叫刘东茂
from the Computer Department.
是计算机系的
This fat guy
这位胖师兄呢
is Zhu Jiafa
叫朱加法
from the Control Department.
他是控制系的
We're responsible for
我们俩主要负责
the mechanical parts of the brain-computer interface.
脑机接口的机械部分
By the way, in our lab,
对了 咱们实验室
there's a senior who is
还有一个学脑外
very good at brain surgery.
特别厉害的大师姐
She's responsible for
她主要负责
the invasive brain-computer interface,
植入式脑机接口
which is to implant a chip in the brain
就是在大脑里植入芯片
to control an external device.
然后控制外部设备
As for Yuhe...
至于小肖
I don't need to say much.
小肖我肯定不用多说了
You must know him well enough.
你肯定都知道啦
He didn't tell me anything.
他没有跟我说过
Sounds fair.
也是
Yuhe doesn't like
小肖这个人在生活中
to talk about himself.
的确不喜欢讨论自己
But with more time,
不过你跟他
you'll gradually
处的时间长了
know him.
会慢慢了解他的
No...
不是
Chengcheng, this way.
师妹 这边请
Go.
走
The Brain and Intelligence Lab
我们脑与智实验室
is a national key lab
是多学科
of multidisciplinary
交叉脑机融合
brain-computer integration.
国家重点实验室
Our three main
我们主要研究
research fields are
植入式脑机接口
invasive bain-computer interface,
非侵入式脑机接口
non-intrusive bain-computer interface,
和人工智能类脑计算
and AI brain-like computing.
三大方向
Top-level lab.
神级实验室
Avatar in real life.
现实版阿凡达
Yes.
对
Avatar used the
阿凡达用的就是
brain-computer interface tech.
脑机接口技术
It's cutting-edge
这是一项
technology,
非常前沿的技术
which can integrate
它可以通过
humans and computers
读取人的脑电信号
by reading EEG signals.
将人机合一
For example, it helps people control
比如 它可以通过意念
robots and mechanical arms through mind.
去操控机械人 机械臂
Meanwhile, it's helpful in solving
同时也可以解决
many medical problems
许多医学难题
like enabling paralyzed patients
比方说可以让瘫痪患者
to regain action competence.
重新获得行动能力
This is the brainwave control.
这个就是脑电波控制
Here, have a try.
来 试试
The more concentrated you are,
注意力越集中
the faster the car runs.
测试跑得越快
Cool!
帅啊
Did you
这个也是
do this with Jiafa?
你跟加法师兄做的吗
Well,
那
absolutely.
必须的
But we did the
但是我们俩主要负责
mechanical part mostly.
机械部分多一点
Yuhe did
至于这个算法嘛
the algorithm.
都是小肖做的
He did?
是他
Yes, he's basically
对 他负责的算法
responsible for algorithms
基本包含了
concerning all our research projects.
我们所有研究的项目
Aren't you recruited by him?
你不是他招进来的吗
Work hard and learn from him.
以后跟他好好学吧
So,
那
will he come to the lab today?
他今天会来实验室吗
Sure. He comes every day.
会啊 他每天都来
Yeah.
对啊
Here he comes.
来了
Speak of the devil.
说曹操曹操到
Here the devil comes.
曹操到了
It's OK.
没事
Thanks, Dongmao.
谢谢师兄
Go ahead.
去吧去吧
Yuhe is dull usually.
你说小肖平时闷不拉叽
Who would think he has such a junior?
突然蹦一学妹出来
I'm going to make her a coffee.
我去给她做杯咖啡吧
Go ahead.
去吧
Yuhe,
师兄
I came to report for duty.
我今天来报到了
They gave me
两位师兄也带我
a tour around the lab.
参观了一下实验室
I saw it.
我看见了
You had a good time.
你们玩得很开心
Anything else?
还有什么事吗
I want to know
我想问一下
why did you let me join the lab?
你为什么让我来实验室
And,
还有
what do you think of
我昨天跟你说的那些话
the thing I told you yesterday?
你到底是怎么想的
During work, I only answer
工作期间我只回答
work-related questions.
跟工作相关的问题
As for unrelated things,
其他的
we can talk after 8:00 PM.
晚上八点以后再说
8:00 PM, right?
八点是吗
OK. I'll wait for you.
行 那我等你
What do you think?
怎么样
Think what?
什么怎么样
Chengcheng.
澄澄啊
It's rare for you
难得第一回
to bring a girlfriend to the lab.
往实验室里带女朋友
Rest assured.
放心
I've arranged for you
师兄给你安排得
clearly and properly.
明明白白 妥妥贴贴
No problem.
没毛病
Have you solved the problem
去噪清晰度的问题
of noise reduction clarity
解决了吗
and improved the accuracy of the singular value
小波分析奇异值的精度
based on wavelet analysis?
提升了吗
Are you really so free?
实验室都这么闲了吗
It only needs an undergraduate
来个本科生
to distract you from work.
都不用工作了
Is there no problem?
还没毛病
Shouldn't you arrange some work
新来的不该安排
for the newcomer?
一些事情做吗
Why are you staring at me?
你看着我干什么
Do I look like wavelet analysis?
我长得很像小波分析
Here. Have a try.
来 尝一尝
This coffee is only served
我这杯咖啡
to those who officially
只有正式进入
join the Brain
我们脑与智实验室的人
and Intelligence Lab.
才能喝得到
No food and drink in the lab.
实验室禁止饮食啊
The cleaning lady
负责保洁的阿姨
asked for a day off today.
今天家里有事来不了了
Newcomer, you clean
新来的待会儿把实验室
the lab later.
打扫一下
Jiafa,
加法
tell her about the dos and don'ts.
跟她交代一下注意事项
Tell her what?
交代什么呀
What?
什么
Xiao Yuhe recruited her...
肖宇河把她招进来
Come here quickly.
快过来过来
Wait.
不是
Tell her what?
交代什么呀
It seems that Yuhe recruited her
小肖把她招进来
not because he
好像对她
felt that way about her.
并没有那个意思
What way?
那个意思是什么意思
That way.
就是那个意思啊
Let me tell you, really...
我跟你说 真的是
So...
那
Yuhe, you're here.
师兄你来了
So,
所以你
what's your answer?
你答复是什么
Does it matter?
这很重要吗
It does.
很重要
When the form is printed out,
等一下表格打印出来
fill in your information.
信息填一下
And then?
然后呢
Conduct brain data acquisition experiment.
做脑数据采集实验
What's a brain data acquisition experiment?
什么是脑数据采集实验
To extract brain data
用专业的设备
with professional devices.
提取脑数据
Didn't you say you liked me?
你不是说你喜欢我吗
You have to prove it in a scientific way.
得用科学的方式来证明
I know clearly that I like you.
我喜欢你我自己知道的
I don't need an experiment.
不用做实验
The word "like" is too abstract
喜欢这个词过于抽象
and unreal.
且不真实
Only scientific data
只有科学数据
won't lie.
是不会骗人的
I didn't lie to you. It's for real.
我没骗你 是真的
Feelings are deceptive.
感情是具有欺骗性的
Maybe you're cheated by yourself,
可能你连你自己都骗了
only that you don't know.
只是你不知道
Fill it in.
填吧
So many?
这么多
How about this,
那这样吧
I ask and you answer me.
我问你答
-Name. -Su Chengcheng.
姓名 苏澄澄
-Native place. -Jinjiang.
籍贯 津江
Name of your elementary school.
小时候上学学校名字
Jinjiang Experimental Primary School.
津江实验小学
Favorite snack in childhood.
童年喜欢的零食
Popsicle. Long
冰棍 长的
and could be broken.
可以掰的那种
Favorite color.
喜欢的颜色
Chromatic colors.
彩色
Be specific.
具体点
Blue, red, yellow...
蓝的 红的 黄
You're passionate.
你挺博爱
Let's say tolerant.
这叫包容
Do you like to make friends?
喜欢交朋友吗
Yes.
喜欢
Do you think it's difficult to make friends?
觉得交朋友难吗
Not at all.
那有什么难的
What's your definition of friends?
你对朋友的界定是什么
Be frank with each other and do anything for each other.
坦诚相待 两肋插刀
How long does friendship last?
友谊的保质期多久
A lifetime.
一辈子
What about love?
那爱情呢
Also a lifetime.
也是一辈子
It turns out that love and friendship
原来爱情和友情
are the same in your eyes.
在你眼里是一样的
You set me in a trap.
你给我下套
Stop it.
我不拍了
The more honest you are,
只有越坦诚
the more accurate the data is.
数据才能越准确
Is that clear?
明白吗
Let me proceed.
我继续问
Do you like your childhood?
喜欢自己的童年吗
Why?
为什么
I can date when I grow up.
长大了能谈恋爱
Didn't you have many friends?
你不是有很多朋友吗
Do you still remember
你还记得小时候
your best friends' names in childhood?
最好的朋友的名字吗
Your best friends.
说最好的
Well, is there something wrong
不是 你这个问题
with your question?
是不是有问题啊
What do my best friends' names
我最好的朋友的名字
have to do with
跟我喜不喜欢你
whether I like you or not?
有什么关系呢
It's used to assess whether
这是在评估你对感情
you are committed to a relationship.
是否专一且长久
Go ahead.
说吧
What are their names?
都叫什么
Wang Lunye.
王伦也
Yuhang.
宇航
Beibei.
贝贝
Mengmeng.
萌萌
And many others.
还有挺多的
Is that all?
完了
You don't know them, anyway.
我说了你也不认识
That's all.
没了
Su Chengcheng.
苏澄澄
Did you really forget me?
你真不记得我了吗